Society of Biological Psychiatry Records Finding Aid
Oskar Diethelm Library
Society of Biological Psychiatry Records
1947 - 1987
This collection contains records from the Society of Biological Psychiatry. The collection has no series and needs to be reprocessed.
5.01 linear feet (8 boxes)
Society of Biological Psychiatry
Oskar Diethelm Library DeWitt Wallace Institute of Psychiatry: History, Policy and the Arts Weill Cornell Medical College 525 East 68th Street, Box 140 New York, NY 10065
1988.0001
Gift of the Society of Biological Psychiatry, 1988.
There are no access restrictions on this material.
The Society of Biological Psychiatry was founded in 1945 to encourage the study of the biological causes and treatments for psychiatric disorders. According to the Society’s statement of purpose, its role “is to promote excellence in scientific research and education in fields that investigate the nature, causes, mechanisms, and treatments of disorders of thought, emotion, or behavior.” The Society is composed mainly of physicians in the fields of neurology, psychiatry, psychology, neurophysiology, electro-encephalography, neuroanatomy, neurosurgery, neuropathology, and neurochemistry who are interested in the biological basis of behavior. Membership is by invitation only and is international in scope. The Society holds annual meetings that include the presentation of papers and scientific exhibits, a President’s reception, and an annual dinner. The official journal of the Society is Biological Psychiatry.
Society of Biological Psychiatry; Society of Biological Psychiatry. Convention & Scientific Program; Biological psychiatry
The collection includes the constitution, bylaws, incorporation papers, and correspondence of officers. There is a limited amount of correspondence of the President, 1969-1981, and the Secretary-Treasurer, 1964-1972. Most of the correspondence pertains to annual meetings, research awards, and other business matters. In addition, some material relates to the World Federation of Societies of Biological Psychiatry. There are also drafts of minutes of the 1980 Executive Council meetings, general correspondence regarding the 1980 and 1981 annual meetings, some financial records, membership dues ledgers providing names and years of membership from 1947-1983, and published programs of the annual conventions and scientific programs from 1963-1987. In addition, the collection includes an incomplete set of printed membership directories from 1980-1987. The collection has no series and needs to be reprocessed.
- No series
  - Constitution and bylaws, 1975 (Box 1)
  - State of California Articles of Incorporation including original constitution and bylaws and membership list, 1973 (Box 1)
  - State of California Articles of Incorporation, 1973 (Box 1)
  - Office of the President – George N. Thompson, 1969 - 1971 (Box 1)
  - Office of the President, 1980 (Box 1)
  - Office of the President – correspondence on seeking donations from pharmaceutical companies, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Office of the Secretary-Treasurer, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Office of the Secretary-Treasurer, 1965 (Box 1)
  - Office of the Secretary-Treasurer, including meeting program, 1966 (Box 1)
  - Office of the Secretary-Treasurer, including membership list, 1967 (Box 1)
  - Office of the Secretary-Treasurer, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Office of the Secretary-Treasurer, 1969 (Box 1)
  - Office of the Secretary-Treasurer, 1969 - 1970 (Box 1)
  - Office of the Secretary-Treasurer, 1971 (Box 1)
  - Office of the Secretary-Treasurer, annual meeting, 1971 (Box 1)
  - Office of the Secretary-Treasurer, 1972 (Box 1)
  - Copies of agenda, financial statements, and minutes, 1972 (Box 1)
  - Journal of Biological Psychiatry, 1968 - 1971 (Box 2)
  - A.E. Bennett Research Award, Gold Medal Award, 1976 - 1979 (Box 2)
  - World Federation of Societies of Biological Psychiatry, proposed withdrawal from World Federation, 1978 (Box 2)
  - World Federation of Societies of Biological Psychiatry, 1979 - 1981 (Box 2)
  - World Federation of Societies of Biological Psychiatry, 1981 (Box 2)
  - Bank records and income correspondence, 1969 - 1971 (Box 2)
  - Financial reports, 1980; 1983 (Box 2)
  - Executive Council agenda, 1980 meeting (Box 2)
  - 1980 meeting – general (Box 2)
  - 1980 annual meeting – general (Box 2)
  - 1981 annual meeting – general (Box 2)
  - Executive Council meeting, 1981 (Box 2)
  - Membership dues ledger A – E, 1960 - 1983 (Box 3)
  - Membership dues ledger F – K, 1959 - 1983 (Box 3)
  - Membership dues ledger L – R, 1966 - 1983 (Box 3)
  - Membership dues ledger S – V, 1959 - 1983 (Box 3)
  - Membership dues ledger W – Z, senior members A – E, 1947 - 1983 (Box 3)
  - Senior members L – Z, corresponding members, 1947 - 1983 (Box 3)
  - Annual convention and scientific programs, 1963 - 1981 (Box 4)
  - Annual convention and scientific programs, 1986 - 1987 (Box 5)
  - Membership directory, 1980 (Box 5)
  - Membership directory, 1983 (Box 5)
  - Membership directory, 1985 - 1986 (Box 5)
  - Membership directory, 1986 - 1987 (Box 5)
  - Executive Council Meeting Minutes, 1967
  - Executive Council Meeting Minutes, 1985
  - Executive Council Meeting Minutes, 1986
  - Executive Council Meeting Minutes, 1987
  - Executive Council Meeting Minutes, 1988
  - Executive Council Meeting Minutes, 1989
  - Internal Revenue Service Tax Exempt Status, 1974
  - Financial Statements and Tax Returns, 1976 - 1984
  - Financial Statements and Tax Returns, 1985
  - Financial Statements and Tax Returns, 1986
  - Financial Statements and Tax Returns, 1987
  - Financial Statements and Tax Returns, 1988
  - Financial Statements and Tax Returns, 1989
  - World Federation of Biological Psychiatry, 1980 - 1989
  - Membership Statistics, 1986
  - Membership Statistics, 1987
  - Membership Statistics, 1988
  - Membership Statistics, 1989
  - Annual Meeting Program, 1987
  - Membership Directory, 1985 - 1986
  - Membership Directory, 1986 - 1987
  - Membership Directory, 1982
  - Membership Directory, 1984
  - Annual Meeting Program, 1988
  - Annual Meeting Program, 1989
  - Membership Directory, 1988 - 1989
  - Award Winners, 1986
  - Award Winners, 1987
  - Award Winners, 1988
  - Award Winners, 1989
  - Pharmaceutical Donations, 1986
  - Pharmaceutical Donations, 1987
  - Pharmaceutical Donations, 1988
  - Pharmaceutical Donations, 1989
  - Annual Meeting Registration, 1986
  - Annual Meeting Registration, 1987
  - Annual Meeting Registration, 1988
  - Annual Meeting Registration, 1989
  - SBP Executive Council Policy Statement Regarding the Use of Limbic System Surgery, 1984
  - Annual Meeting Guest Register, 1969 - 1989